let's look at the solution to our
distributed last level cache we have 16
cores in a four by four mesh it doesn't
really matter what the organization of
the network is we need to know that
there are really 16 tiles
numbered 0 through 15
and that we have an 8 megabyte cache
with 256 byte block 16 way set
associative distributed round robin by
set so set 0 will be in slice 0 set 1
will be in slice 1 etc and then it just
wraps around so let's look at
what this address maps to
the least significant
8 bits are telling us what the block
offset is
the next so many bits are going to be
the index and the least significant bits
of the index are going to tell us which
tile to look at
there are 16 tiles
so the next digit is really the tile
number
and that means
that we go to tile number six
note that we don't really need to even
compute what exactly is the index
because the least significant bits in
this case are telling us
what we need to know